pressdisplay.com 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy – PressReader Care

**Version Effective Date:** February 11, 2019

This document has updated the definition of children to persons under the age of 16 (Section 13. Watch the Kids). In the previous version of the policy, children were described as those under the age of 13.

  1. **About this policy**
  2. **Information covered by this policy**
  3. **It’s all about you**
  4. **Some Personal Information is required to access certain features or Services**
  5. **We might ask for more Personal Information**
  6. **We automatically collect certain information**
  7. **Cookies (not the chocolate chip kind)**
  8. **When we disclose Personal Information**
  9. **How we use and disclose Anonymous Information**
  10. **Your Personal Information may be transferred**
  11. **You’re in control of your Personal Information**
  12. **Taking security seriously**
  13. **Watch the Kids**
  14. **Spam**
  15. **Ch-ch-changes (to this Privacy Policy)**
  16. **Any Questions?**
  17. **Who’s in charge around here?**

We know your privacy is important to you.  It’s important to us, too. So this Privacy Policy will help you, as a user of the Services, understand what information we may gather about you, how we use it, and how we work to protect it.  This Privacy Policy forms part of the [Terms of Use](https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/articles/206528495-Terms-of-Use) that govern your use of the Services.  Defined terms not otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy are defined in the Terms of Use. In visiting the Websites, downloading the App or otherwise using the Services, you are consenting to the information practices outlined in this Privacy Policy, and to the Terms of Use.

Basically, if you’re using PressReader, you agree to this Privacy Policy.   If you don’t agree (but we hope you will), don’t use PressReader, and delete your account. 

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information.  “ **Personal Information** ” is personally identifiable information that can be used to contact you or determine your identity.  When other information is linked to this personally identifiable information, it may also become Personal Information.

Depending on the privacy laws where you live, Personal Information may include your name, personal email address, phone number, billing information, shipping address, device ID, or account login credentials, such as your login for sites like Facebook, Twitter, Google, or other third party websites or apps (your “ **Social Logins** ”).  

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information that you provide to us, or Personal Information provided to us on your behalf by a third party, including through a Social Login.   

We want to be clear: unless we or a third party tells you otherwise, we won’t ask a third party to hand over your Personal Information in order for us to provide you with the Services.  This Privacy Policy does _not_ apply to the practices of those third parties with respect to how they themselves collect or use Personal Information in the course of their own business.   Also, this Privacy Policy doesn’t cover any advertisements from third parties you may see while using our Services, nor does it cover content in the Services that links to third party websites.  You’ll have to check with them to find their privacy policy.    

Readers are at the center of every decision we make at PressReader.  We collect, use, share and process your Personal Information, we promise it’s not to creep you out, but only to make your PressReader experience even better.   By “better” we mean, customized to you – we want to recommend stories and content we think you’ll love, and allow you to save and share the ones you do.     

If you want to get technical about it, there are a number of reasons we collect and use your Personal Information.  For example, we do so in order to deliver the Services to you as required by the Terms of Use, including providing customer support to you when you need it.  We also use it to comply with our contractual obligations to our publishing partners, and to help our product development team build a better PressReader product that better reflects your interests.

Certain features or Services will only be available to you if you create a Registered Account.  When you create a Registered Account, we ask you for basic registration information, including your name and email address or Social Login.  This is the minimum information you will need to provide in order to create a Registered Account.   You will be required to create a Registered Account to fully use and enjoy the features associated with a Trial, Subscription, Single Issue Purchase, or Gifted Issue.

If you purchase a Subscription or make a Single Issue Purchase, we will also collect billing information such as your credit card number, expiry date, and billing address.

Sponsored Access may not necessarily require you to create a Registered Account.

We may ask you to volunteer additional Personal Information at other times, such as when you provide opinions, post a Submission, enter a contest or promotion, or report a problem with the Services.    You can choose not to provide us with this additional Personal Information, but it may mean that you cannot take advantage of the features, Services, contests or promotions associated with our request.

When you submit a request for support or information, PressReader will keep a record of that support or information request, and the manner in which it was handled by us.

We also collect information about you as a user so we can make your experience more personal. We automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, your computer or device’s name, the type and version of your web browser, referrer addresses, mobile device IDs, location information derived from GPS or similar features on your mobile device (where you have enabled such features and where you have given us permission to collect this information), date/time stamp, and other generally-accepted log information. We also record page views (hit counts), and capture information about your reading behavior.  

A cookie is a small amount of data which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website’s computers and stored on your computer’s hard drive.  Each website can send its own cookies to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it. However, to protect your privacy, most browsers only permit a website to access the cookies that the same website has already sent to you, _not_ the cookies sent to you by other sites.

PressReader sets and accesses our own cookies on your computer.  We use them to identify you as a repeat visitor, to maintain session information for logged-in users, and to track usage trends and patterns. That helps us better understand and improve areas of the Websites. 

PressReader also allows third parties who are providing content on our Websites to set and access their own cookies on your computer.  Third parties’ use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies.  We do not have access to any information stored by third parties about you.

You can find more information about the types of cookies that we use on the [Cookies](https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000868863-Cookies) page.

In general, we will not disclose Personal Information to unaffiliated third parties without your express consent.  However, there may be circumstances where we may need to disclose Personal Information about you to an unaffiliated third party.  For instance:

  * When PressReader employs other third parties to perform functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders, providing customer service, sending mail, processing credit card payments, processing currency conversions, or other functions necessary to our business;
  * If publishers of the Publications request additional Personal Information from us. The information practices of those publishers will be governed by their own privacy policies;
  * If we believe you are harming or interfering with the enjoyment of the Services of other PressReader users, anyone else, or violating the terms of your Subscription, Trial, Sponsored Access or Gifted Issue, or violating the Terms of Use, or if we believe you are infringing any of PressReader or a third party’s legal rights;
  * If we are required by applicable law (or court order) to provide any of your Personal Information. We will, if permitted by applicable law or the terms of a court order, attempt to notify you via the email address you supplied when creating your Registered Account before we respond to the request;
  * In the event of a sale of all or most of PressReader’s assets, this information may be transferred to the purchaser so they may continue to provide the Services to you.

**“Anonymous Information”** is any information other than Personal Information, including aggregated information that we derive from Personal Information.  We make sure that Anonymous Information does not include any Personal Information.

PressReader may use Anonymous Information:

  * To improve the Websites, the App, and the Services;
  * To deliver the Services;
  * To monitor traffic and general usage patterns;
  * To inform publishers as to what content is appealing to certain users of the Services;
  * To inform advertisers of the usage habits or characteristics of certain users of the Services;
  * To advise potential investors so that they may better understand the PressReader user base; and
  * To provide you with an improved experience when using the Websites, the App, and the Services.

PressReader has headquarters in Canada, Ireland and the Philippines, all of which work together to seamlessly provide you with the Services.  Basically, we’re one big happy PressReader family.  If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) or Switzerland, what you need to know is that PressReader International Limited (“ **PRI** ”), located in Dublin, Ireland, is the controller of your Personal Information, as described in applicable data protection law.  

PressReader has data processing agreements and security controls in place between the PressReader group of companies, to ensure the safety and security of your Personal Information as it’s shared between us.  In using the Services, you consent to us sharing your Personal Information within the PressReader group of companies to the extent required to provide the Services to you. 

If you’re located outside of Canada or the Philippines and choose to use the Services or give us any Personal Information, you’re agreeing and understanding that your Personal Information will be transferred, processed and stored in Canada and the Philippines, as it is necessary for us to provide the Services to you and to fulfil our obligations to you under the Terms of Use.  

You have control over your Personal Information and can change your Registered Account, Subscription information, or other information saved by us, including how much of your Personal Information is publicly available in your profile, by visiting the Website and reviewing your settings.

If you’d like a copy of the Personal Information that PressReader has saved, you can ask us for it anytime, by contacting us here: <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>.  

If you want to delete your Registered Account, Subscription Information or other information saved by us, contact us here: <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>.  We’ll be sad to see you go, but your information will then be deleted, assuming that: (a) you are current with all payment obligations regarding any Subscriptions you have purchased or Single Issue Purchases you have made; (b) PressReader does not believe it is reasonably necessary to keep such information in accordance with applicable law or any pending legal action; and (c) we are under no other legal obligation to retain such information.  If your information is deleted, any unfulfilled Subscriptions will be cancelled without refund and you may have to re-register with PressReader in order to use the Services.

You can also object to any aspect of how we process your Personal Information based on what we’ve set out in this Privacy Policy, or revoke your consent to this Privacy Policy, lock stock and barrel, at any time, by contacting us at <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>.  Where you’ve objected to an aspect of how we process your Personal Information or revoked your consent to this Privacy Policy, we will stop providing the Services to you.

The TL;DR version?  If you have any complaints or concerns about your Personal Information or how PressReader uses it, just hit us up at <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>.  We’re here for you. 

PressReader uses reasonable and up-to-date security methods to prevent unauthorized access to Personal Information. Seriously. We work hard to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure correct use of Personal Information.

Your Personal Information will be stored within a database behind a firewall for added security. The server that houses the database is physically protected at a secure site and is monitored by security personnel twenty-four hours a day.  Only authorized personnel can access the site and the particular server housing the database.

No data transmission over the internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be secure.  So, while we try to protect your Personal Information, we can’t ensure or guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.  We encrypt all information and web sessions within the Services that are required to be encrypted, such as transmission of credit card information to the Websites or the App, to help protect the data.

The Services offered by PressReader are not directed to children (persons under the age of 16) and we do not knowingly collect, either online or offline, Personal Information of children under the age of 16, except where a parent or guardian has authorized its collection.  If you believe the Personal Information of a child under the age of 16 has been provided to us without parental or guardian consent, please notify us at <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>. 

We don’t want to spam you, but we do periodically send emails to users with Registered Accounts that we think are helpful. They might talk about changes to the features of the Services, the addition of new issues of your favorite Publications, promotions, or other fun stuff.  You can always opt out of PressReader’s marketing or promotional messaging by adjusting the settings in your Registered Account.  Sorry, but you can’t opt out of billing, legal, or account-related emails.

We might change the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time.  If we do make changes regarding the disclosure of your Personal Information, we will post a super-obvious notice of the new-and-improved Privacy Policy on the Websites (you might get an email from us, too).  Your continued use of the Services after we’ve posted notice of any change to this Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of those changes.

We have answers.  Give us a shout here: <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new>.

While the entire PressReader team takes your privacy seriously, the head honcho on all things privacy is our Chief Privacy Officer, Nikolay Malyarov.  You can direct inquiries about anything privacy-related here: <https://care.pressreader.com/hc/en-us/requests/new> and we’ll make sure it’s addressed.

You can also snail mail us at:

PressReader Inc.

200-13111 Vanier Place

Richmond, BC, Canada

V6V 2J1

Attention: Legal

or to

PressReader International Limited

2nd Floor, The Boat House, Bishop Street

Dublin 8, Ireland D08H01F

Attention: Legal
